AKASH NAIR

Berlin

+49 0176 323 76787 akashon1@gmail.com www.skywide.in

PERSONAL PROFILE

I am a DevOps engineer with nearly 3 years of experience on AWS, DevOps practices and infrastructure management. I am seeking opportunities where I can use my skills to design and implement solutions that can improve and increase the velocity of software development

WORK EXPERIENCE

Sparwelt GmbH, Germany | DevOps Engineer

SEPTEMBER 2018 - PRESENT

Microservice deployment on Kubernetes
CI/CD Pipeline implementation using Jenkins
Optimisation of microservices using Docker
Management of AWS accounts and services
Monitoring and logging of application using Datadog

Key Skills: Kubernetes, Jenkins, Docker, AWS, SCRUM, Datadog

PTC Software, India | Software Analyst

JULY 2016 - SEPTEMBER 2017

Implementation of CI/CD pipelines for development teams using Jenkins
Automation of processes and tasks using Python, Shell scripting
Provisioning of infrastructure whenever required
Configuration management using Ansible
Ensuring smooth deployments to production and test systems

Key Skills: Jenkins, Ansible, Docker, Shell Scripting, SCRUM, VPN, Papertrail

BlazeClan Technologies, India | Cloud Engineer

DECEMBER 2014 - JUNE 2016

Design of Highly Scalable and Fault Tolerant Architectures on the cloud
Migration of on-premise infrastructure to AWS
Configuration and troubleshooting of servers & networks
Optimisation of infrastructure and operations
Conducting routine security audits of systems and networks

Key Skills: AWS, Vagrant, Python, Linux/Unix, Cloud Migration, Disaster Recovery, Solution Architecture

EDUCATION

University	of Pune,	India	Bachelors in	Computer Science
------------	----------	-------	--------------	-------------------------

AUGUST 2009 - APRIL 2012

University of Pune, India | Master of Computer Applications

AUGUST 2012 - APRIL 2015

Frankfurt UAS, Germany | Masters in High Integrity Systems

OCTOBER 2017 - MARCH 2018

CERTIFICATIONS

Python Data Structures - University of Michigan on Coursera

☐ Certificate earned at Monday, March 7, 2016

Using Python to Access Web Data - University of Michigan on Coursera

☐ Certificate earned at Monday, June 13, 2016

AWS Certified SysOps Administrator – Associate

- ☐ Successfully completed the AWS Certification requirements and gained recognition as a AWS Certified Solutions Architect
- ☐ Certificate AWS-ASOA-6871

SKILLS & INTERESTS

Skills:

- ☐ Proficient in English writing and speaking
- Basic knowledge of German
- Python programming
- AWS services
- ☐ Terraform and Infrastructure-as-Code

Interests:

Solo travelling, playing guitar, hiking, meeting new people, reading history books, urban exploration